Hello everyone my name is Rahul so I have
completed one month as
SA Senior Officer in ICICI Bank so my one month is
completed so what all did I
experience and what did I
get less what was the work what was the pressure what was the
target what target is given in starting
and how is your training done
and also what salary do you get
when do you get it and how much do you get,
we will discuss all that in this video so
before that let's talk about
how I got selected in ICICI Bank so I do
n't have any background in banking I didn't have any
banking background and I have
n't done any course like Time
Bro or Nit Program I haven't
done anything I was completely fresh in banking I did
n't have any banking background so
I went to the career portal and
applied directly after that
then I got the link for the interview and then I
gave the interview and got selected on my interview
I gave the interview very well I had given the interview after very
good preparation so
because of that I got selected
how to apply in ICICI Bank  There's a
video, you can go and watch it. To get
selected in a bank, you have an
interview. But if you do
n't have any banking background, then there are
other factors besides the interview that are
very important. If you
follow them step by step, your
chances of getting selected in the interview will be higher.
If you
want a video on how to crack a bank
interview with this, I'll discuss everything and
make a video and upload it for you. Let
me know in the comments below if you
want a video or not. Okay, so now let's talk about
training. In your initial induction,
you're given a general
overview, but the rest of the work you do,
you have to learn in the branch itself. So let's
talk about how that training happens. This is
n't a corporate office, so no
one comes here and gives you a PPT,
shows you a PPT, and
trains you in a classroom. Nothing like that happens for
hours. Okay, so nothing like this happens
in the banking sector.
I'm not talking about just one bank.  I am
telling you about all the banks, they are of this
type, so some HRS will
not give you a proper class, no one
gives you any such PPT or PDF, in this
you have to learn by yourself,
if someone is doing many things then you will go and sit near him,
you will learn by watching what he is doing, that is, you learn by watching, if
someone is opening an account then
you will stand next to him and see how he is opening the account,
as he opens the account
you will
see the process, he will tell you and in this way
you will learn, suppose it is a credit card then
if you do not know anything about the offer, then you
can ask all these questions
and then you will ask yourself questions too and
whatever doubts you have, you should keep noting them in your diary
and in this way you will learn and
brother, I joined in the month of March, so
in the month of March everyone is already
very busy because all of you have your own target
pressure, even if it is
not the month of March, still everyone gets their work done  If your target
pressure is given then they achieve it, then
when will they get time to train you because they have
less time of their own, they have their own report, they have to work on it, so in this way
you will have to learn everything by asking more, so now let's talk about what work was given to
me in a month, what
target and what was the pressure on me, it was the
first month so I was
not given that much target pressure, but the rest of the
staff, there was a lot of
target pressure on them, so I
saw everyone there and observed, they were given a
lot of target because
pressure is given to you as to why your target is
not being achieved, or it is the month of March, that
means in this you have to
deliver, in fact I was also told to make
sales and I did it,
I also contributed a lot, so
if you join in the month of March then friend you are
told a little early to make
sales, so normally if you
join a bank then your one and a half month is
spent in learning things like this,
but if you join during this time  If you do this, there might be a
little more pressure, so I used to
stay in the branch very rarely, I was
not sent out to the field, I had to
go to the field and ask all the stores, all the shops whether they had
any retirement or not,
or I had to go out and
make clients, this is how I used to work,
so now let's talk about the timing, the
original timing of the bank is from 9:00 am to
6:00 pm, this type of bank
timing is but I have
also stayed in the bank till 8:30 pm, okay, this March,
what should I say, it was the month of March, there was
a big meeting, so I had to stay for that, there was
a big meeting, all the
people were there, so I also had to stay, so it happened only once that
I had to stay till 8:30 pm, the
rest of the time
we would normally leave the bank by 6:30 pm, so you may have to
extend a little bit in all this time,
so it is very important for you to know this thing,
now  Let's talk about salary, I got my
salary,
I said I got the full salary because
my induction started on 1st February
and then whatever I got, in normal banking
sector, you get your salary on the last day of your working day, that is
28th, so
my salary was paid on 28th itself and
I got the full salary because
my induction started from the first date, so
your salary is calculated from the first day of induction,
if I join in the middle, say 5th
February or 10th February, then I get less money for these days,
but if I was inducted from 1st date, then I got the
full money, I got the
full salary, now let's talk about
how the salary structure is, so brother, look,
you will
not get that CTC, but let's
talk about how much they get, so I
cannot tell you the direct salary
because I cannot tell the bank policy on this,
but I will give you an idea,
suppose if your salary is Rs. 300000  It is of
3 lakhs, okay, if I have a package of 3 lakhs,
if you divide it by 12, it
becomes 25000, but your gross
salary will be ₹20000, and
in 20000 also, PF is deducted, it is
deducted between 1500 to 2000,
so your net salary is ready from 18000 something,
when the salary is 25000, then the
salary you will get will be 18000 something, that
means around 67000 gets deducted from you,
and it is not fixed that only
6000-7000 will be deducted, if someone is on a lower post, then
his deduction is different, if he is
on a higher post, then his deduction can also be
higher, it is
not fixed that your salary will be deducted from whatever your package is, it can be
more, it can be
less, it can be more than that, so
overall  Experience: I have just
joined the bank, so I haven't been told much in a month,
but I feel
that there will be a lot of pressure in the coming time
because gradually I am going to
teach you people, so
their expectations will also be from me, so
when I complete three months,
I will make a video on that as well, so
you will know what happens in the bank.
First, I am telling you about the entire bank,
type this in the bank itself,
and in the upcoming videos, I will
also discuss the job roles of assistant manager, deputy manager and others. Even if
you are not getting hired for that post, it is still
important for you to know
who does what work in the bank because I
always say that it is
very important for you to know the concept. So if you are still going to
join the bank, you
can do it comfortably because it is going to end in March, so
you can join. There is a lot of
pressure on the target, it is
less in the beginning, but
gradually it will increase because
in the beginning you have no base, so to
whom will you sell?  Gradually,
you will start taking time to make clients and you will
learn to work less than 1:00, then you will start
achieving your targets quickly. So, if you
need some tips for selection in the bank, then
tell me, I will make a video on that
and if you have any question, then
ask me in the comment below. You
can also follow me on Instagram, I keep
giving job information there and also
information about banking, so you
can also message me on Instagram, I may be
busy but I will try to reply to you as soon as possible.
Thank you so much for
watching this video. Take care, bye.
Jai Hind and Happy Holi.